Preliminary Guide to the Classics Department records, 1963-1996 RG0130
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Classics Department records
1963-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Knox, Bernard MacGregor Walker
RG0130
6.25 Linear Feet 2 Full Hollinger boxes, 2 Half Hollinger boxes, 4 Paige Cartons (filed letter)
This collection contains information on the Bernard Knox lectures, departmental correspondence, student information and exams, programs, and class syllabi. They range in date from 1963-1996.
Restrictions on Access
Series 1 is closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains information on the Bernard Knox lectures, departmental correspondence, student information and exams, programs, and class syllabi. They range in date from 1963-1996.
Collection Organization
This collection is organized into four series three department record series and Professor Bernard Knox lectures.
Examinations; Courses and lectures
- Department records, 1963-1988; RG0130 Series 1; 1.5 linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes information on the Bernard Knox lectures, departmental records, prizes, M.A. student information and exams. They range in date from 1963-1988.
  Formerly Acc# 61
  This series has a paper container list in the reading room, please ask staff for assistance.
- Department records, 1964-1996; RG0130 Series 2; .25 linear feet
  This series includes correspondence, flyers, faculty lists, programs, schedules, and papers from the Classics department. They range in date from 1964-1996.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Classics Department, 1964-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Department records, 1967-2005; RG0130 Series 3; 6.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
  This series includes information on seminars, correspondence, course syllabi, lectures, and exams. There is also course material written by faculty. The material ranges in date from 1967-2005.
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    General note
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mediterranean Seminar Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Biographical information for Mediterranean Seminar, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fellowships and Grants, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ETA SIGMA PHI, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ETA SIGMA PHI, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - PHI BETA KAPPA, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - University Memorandum, 1991-2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Final Exams, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Finals, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Exams, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Exams, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fall Exams, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fall spring and summer Exams, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Spring final exams, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fall final exams, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Final exams, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Final Exams, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Final Exams, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Seminar, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mediterranean Seminar, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Placement Tests Latin, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Latin Placement Tests (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Placement Test Arabic, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hebrew Placement (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Latin Bowl Questions, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Organization Plan, 1976-1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Course Syllabi, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Summer Course Syllabi and Exams, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Course Syllabi and Exams, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Final Exams, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Course Syllabi and Exams, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Course Syllabi and Exams, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Course Syllabi, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Course Syllabi and Exams, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Course Syllabi, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Syllabi, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fall Syllabi, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Spring Syllabi, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Spring Syllabi, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fall Syllabi, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Spring Syllabi, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fall Syllabi, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Spring Syllabi, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fall Syllabi, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Spring Syllabi, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Spring Syllabi, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Lectures, 1978-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Promotion tenure and sabbatical information, 1997-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ETA SIGMA PHI certificates, 1973-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Assistance Program - childcare, 1988-1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - CCAS meetings, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ETA SIGMA PHI programs, 1976-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ETA SIGMA PHI National Convention, 1967-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ancient Mediterranean Cultures Seminar members, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Department of Classics correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lectures, 1981-1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Study of the Classics by Elizabeth Fisher, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Biblical Roots of Western Civilization by Robert Jones, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Introduction to the Discipline of Philosophy by Jonathan Moreno, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Outline of History by Robert Hadley, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - What is Humanistic Education a report of a conference of the Dilthey Society of George Washington University, 10/27/1973; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ideas in Western Culture: Aquinas to Locke Course Manual by James Burks, Paul Churchill, Robert Kenny, Gail Paster, Jon Quitslund, Ormond Seavey, and Dewey Wallace, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Western Civilization an Owner's Manual compiled by Ormond Seavey in conjunction with: David Altshuler, Elizabeth Fisher, Robert Hadley, Robert Jones, Jonathan Moreno & John Ziolkowski, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Professor Bernard Knox lectures, 1981-1984; Series 4; Knox, Bernard MacGregor Walker; 0.5 Linear Feet 25 audio cassettes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains audio cassette recordings of Professor Bernard Knox lectures. These tapes were originally given to the Media Resources department at Gelman Library as a reserve. Media transferred these two the Classics Department when Dr. Knox was no longer teaching. Dr. John Ziolkowski gave them to the University Archives.
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece [1/9], 10/18/1981; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 1)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece [2/9], 10/24/1981; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 2)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece Hessiod Works and D. [3/9], 10/31/1981; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 3)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece Homer, Odyssey I [4/9], 11/14/1981; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 4)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece Homer, Odyssey II [5/9], 11/21/1981; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 5)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece Homer, Odyssey III [6/9], 12/05/1981; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 6)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece Lyric Poetry [7/9], 01/30/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 7)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece [8/9], 02/06/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 8)
  - Lecture by Bernard M. W. Knox Archaic Greece [Bachylides] [9/9], 02/13/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 9)
  - Lecture by Bernard Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Introduction [1/10], 10/09/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 10)
  - Lecture by Bernard Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Introduction [2/10], 10/16/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 11)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Agamemnon I [3/10], 10/30/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 12)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Agamemnon II [4/10], 11/06/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 13)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Agamemnon III [5/10], 11/13/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 14)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Choephori (libation bearer) [6/10], 12/04/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 15)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Choephori (libation bearer) [7/10], 12/11/1982; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 16)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Eumenides I [8/10], 02/1983; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 17)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Oresteia Eumenides 2 [9/10], 02/26/1983; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 18)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox The 'Oresteia' of Aeschylus Eumenides III [10/10], 03/05/1983; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 19)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Archaic 10, undated; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 20)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Mythology I [1/5], 03/03/1984; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 21)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Q and A Mythology II [2/5], 03/10/1984; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 22)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Greek Mythology III [3/5], 03/17/1984; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 23)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Mythology IV [4/5], 03/24/1984; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 24)
  - Lecture by Bernard W. Knox Mythology V [5/5], 03/31/1984; Series 4 (Box 6, Cassette 25)